紙牌屋
前情提要
翻譯   草草
翻譯   國士章魚X
翻譯   杏仁斯嘉麗
翻譯   煮粥
翻譯   吃冰棒
翻譯   肉松
時間軸   壬虛浪影
時間軸   念念
時間軸   西·查
后期   餓得慌
顧問   老杜
校對   草草
總監   草草
紙牌屋
人人影視傾情奉獻
第五季  第五集
艾·麥卡倫莉  我受不了了  對不起  麥卡...
諾克斯維爾投票中心發生事故
田納西州
諾克斯維爾
諾克斯維爾投票中心疏散
田納西州諾克斯維爾
部分州不能認證結果
不要安德伍德
廢除總統選舉團
國會將于四天后選定總統
你和我有共同點
You and I have some things in common.
我們都討厭總統
We both dislike the president.
你和安德伍德總統熟悉嗎  先生
How well do you know President Underwood, sir?
我認識總統4年了
I've known the president four years.
是弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
Isn't it a fact that it was Francis Underwood
而不是沃克總統最先建議你辭職的吧
and not President Walker who first suggested you should resign?
發動不了嗎
Having trouble starting it?
是的  可能電池沒電了吧
Yeah. I think the battery might be dead.
如果你想試試跨接啟動  我有電線
I have some cables if you want to try and jump it.
這真的不麻煩嗎
You sure you don't mind?
一點也不
Not at all.
有消息源稱  不久前
Sources are telling us that Francis Underwood
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德致電康威州長
conceded to Governor Conway on the phone
承認落選
only a short time ago.
我猜測他們收到的數字跟我們的相符
I suspect their numbers are matching up with ours.
我不在乎他輸不輸
I don't care if he loses.
我不是指選舉  我是說你
I'm not talking about the election. I'm talking about you.
你會怎么樣
What will happen to you?
持續的恐怖主義威脅帶來的恐慌...
...fear from continued terrorist threats
和田納西州傳出的令人不安的消息
and the disturbing news coming out of Tennessee...
讓我不得不關閉幾個我們的投票站
I was forced to close a number of our polling places.
操
Fuck me.
至少六個州將不能在2016的選舉夜
At least six states will not have certified vote totals
認證計票結果
on Election Night 2016.
怎么  你以為我沒從戈爾那里學到教訓嗎
What? You think I learned nothing from Al Gore?
-不是我的總統  -不是我的總統
- Not my president! - Not my president!
人民很憤怒
The people are angry.
九周前  我們國家舉行了一場大選
Nine weeks ago, we had an election in this country,
但是由于兩個州拒絕認證選舉結果
but because two states refused to certify,
康威和我都沒拿到270張選舉人票
neither Conway nor myself received the 270 electoral votes
而這是勝選的必要條件
required for victory.
所以他們每天早上聚集在這里
So they gather here every morning
來履行他們神圣的權利
to exercise their magnificent right,
被第一修正案保障的權利
guaranteed by the First Amendment...
發出他們憤怒的聲音
to let their angry voices be heard.
就這樣  感恩節  圣誕節
And so, Thanksgiving, Christmas,
再加上半個一月來了又去
and half of January have come and gone,
政府的三大分支全都深陷危機
and all three branches of government are in crisis.
國會吵成一團
The Congress is in disarray,
最高法院少了一位法官  必將陷入僵局
the Supreme Court is down a justice and doomed to deadlock,
而行政機關也群龍無首
and the executive branch is without a boss.
你看  我覺得
You see, my feeling is,
國父們就是乏了
I think the Founding Fathers, they just got tired.
說真的  誰能怪他們呢
And really, can you blame them?
你怎么可能把方方面面都考慮周全
I mean, you can't think of everything.
各種意外  各種難以避免的災難
Black swans, Murphy's Law.
到了一定程度
I mean, at a certain point,
你也只能放棄  交叉手指
you just have to sign off and cross your goddamn fingers
祈求能有個好結果
and hope for the best.
或者使用"扔硬幣原理"
Or adopt "flipism,"
這是一種偽哲學  意思是
a pseudo-philosophy of life in which
生活中最重要的事都要通過扔硬幣來決定
the most important decisions are made by the flipping of a coin.
這個說法最先出現在迪士尼的漫畫書
It was first introduced in the Disney comic book
《硬幣決定法》里  我最喜歡這期了
Flip Decision, one of my favorites,
里面講到巴蒂教授說服唐老鴨
in which Donald Duck is persuaded by Professor Batty
所有重大的人生決定
to make all the most important decisions
都通過扔硬幣來決斷
based on the flipping of a coin.
"生活就是場賭博
"Life is but a gamble.
讓扔硬幣原理指引你"
Let flipism guide your ramble."
我們以前也有過這種麻煩
We've had this sort of trouble before.
1800年大選  杰斐遜對伯爾
The election of 1800, Jefferson versus Burr.
他們最后打成了平手  每人73張選舉人票
They wound up in a tie. 73 electoral votes each.
那是當時的勝選票數
That was the number required then,
這時國會試圖解決這種
and that's when Congress tried to address
國父們根本想象不到的局面
what the Founding Fathers just couldn't imagine.
于是  第十二修正案誕生了
And, poof, the Twelfth Amendment was born.
里面說  如果各州不能認證選舉結果
And it says that if the states don't certify,
那么就由眾議院來挑選總統
it's the House that chooses the president
由參議院來選副總統
and the Senate that chooses the vice president.
眾議院有點亂  說不清楚
Now the House is a bit of a mess,
但是參議院選副總統的辦法可是挺民主的
but the Senate is rather democratic in how they choose the VP.
一人一票
One person, one vote.
但如果還是平局
But if there's a tie...
就該唐老鴨登場了
and this is where Donald Duck comes in,
選舉的結果
it's resolved...
全看這硬幣一扔
by the toss of a coin.
這辦法簡潔得見了鬼
A solution that's elegant as hell.
不過現代政治哪有什么簡潔可言
But then there's no elegance in modern politics.
只剩下見鬼了
It's mostly hell.
美國總統的寶座花落誰家
The identity of the next President of these United States
決定權再次落到了這一幫
is once again in the hands of a bunch of
自私自利  嗜財如命
self-serving, money-hungry,
阿諛諂媚  貪戀權勢的政治家手里
boot-licking, power-seeking politicians
而加以利誘  或者迎頭痛擊
who can be seduced or sucker punched
或者要挾就能讓他們服從
or blackmailed into submission.
我只需要比另一個人多一票就行
And all I need is just one more vote than the other guy.
如你所見  國父們根本沒想到會有這種局面
As you can see, the Founding Fathers didn't plan for this.
而我想到了
But I did.
我就是你的新爹
Meet your new daddy.
好
Right.
你能感覺到  對吧  簡直身臨其境
You can feel it, right? It's like you're there.
是不是跟真的一樣
Doesn't that look just like it?
在我看來簡直就是那個地方
To me, it is that place.
你還好吧
You okay, man?
好  當然好了
Yeah. Of course.
真的有幫助  很管用的
It really helps. Very effective.
是啊  我很樂意幫你拉更多投資來
Yeah. I'd be happy to help you find more funding for it.
如果你情緒有點激動的話
If you're feeling a little worked up...
什么
What?
情緒激動
Little worked up?
兩個多月以前我就當選成為美國總統了
I was elected President of the United States over two months ago.
但不知為何  現在國會將決定選舉結果
But somehow, Congress is now deciding the election.
所以原諒我有些
So forgive me for being a little...
-威爾  -情緒激動
- Will... - ...worked up.
東尼應該不是話中有話
I don't think Tony was implying anything.
當然  那好
Of course. Good.
我去準備一下
I'm gonna get myself ready.
我可不想這副樣子去參加活動
I don't want to go to the event looking like this.
是啊
Right.
謝謝  東尼
Thanks, Tony.
羅梅洛的幕僚長堅稱他不在這兒
Romero's chief of staff insists he's not in town.
-你相信她嗎  -不
- And do you believe her? - No.
但她在特區待得比他久
But she's been in D.C. longer than he has.
她總會顧及自己的
At some point she'll take care of herself.
你告沒告訴她  我不想跟他談
Well, did you tell her I have no interest in discussing
宣戰委員會的事
the Declaration of War Committee with him?
我表明了
I expressed our desire
我們想跟議員進行一次客氣而有成效的談話
for a civil and productive meeting with the Congressman.
找到他
Well, find him.
要是他想躲著我
If he wants to hide from me,
那就當著我的面做
he can do it to my face.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
還有  道格
And, Doug.
今天外面有多少抗議者
How many protestors are out there today?
比昨天多
More than yesterday.
但他們已經盡力
But they're doing their best
讓他們遠離白宮了
to divert them away from the White House.
我不知道哪樣更糟
I don't know what's worse...
是他們抗議喊口號的聲音
the sound of their chanting
還是他們不喊時的寂靜
or the sound of silence when they're not.
我去工作了  先生
I'll get to work, sir.
早上好  奧古斯都
Good morning, Augustus.
艾瑞克  我...
Well, Eric, I...
抱歉  他們讓我坐著  但
I'm sorry. They told me to sit, but, uh--
沒事  完全沒關系  我
No, no, no. It's perfectly fine. I...
我想不到還有誰
I can't imagine anyone else who would...
會比你更喜歡這個
well, enjoy this more than you.
我們在斯波特瑟爾韋尼亞相遇后
You know, I only started it
我才開始做的這個
after you and I met in Spotsylvania.
你對細節的注重簡直是
The attention to detail is... It's just...
沒錯
It is, yes.
我有
I've got...
我
I mean, I...
抱歉  我現在有點不知所錯
I'm sorry, I'm a... a little overwhelmed by the moment.
就是
It's just...
我有一種感覺  就好像
I have this feeling, as if, uh...
我曾經想象過這個場景
I've imagined this somehow.
我知道這聽起來
I know that sounds, uh...
你連他背包上的扣子都做出來了
You've even got the button on his haversack.
是啊
Yes.
我覺得人們會低估
I think people underestimate...
注重細節
the importance of detail...
對整體感覺的影響
to the overall impact.
是啊
Yeah.
血腥角專家肯定會非常欽佩的
The Bloody Angle experts would be very impressed.
我們在斯波特瑟爾韋尼亞相遇時  你怎么知道
When we met in Spotsylvania, how did you know...
那么多關于奧古斯都的細節
so many specific things about Augustus, uh...
關于奧古斯都·安德伍德之死
about Augustus Underwood's death?
知道他犧牲的確切地點
I mean, the very spot where he died?
知道他的腦袋被石頭砸扁了
The... the fact that his skull had been crushed with a rock?
知道他們把他葬在無名冢里
That they buried him in an unmarked grave? I mean...
這么多細節
the detail of all that.
希望你能原諒我
Hope you'll forgive me, uh...
原諒什么
For?
我那天見到了副總統弗蘭西斯·安德伍德
I was meeting Vice President Francis Underwood.
我覺得應該給他講個精彩的傳說
I... thought he deserved a good story.
慢著  等等
Wait, wait a minute. You...
-那些全是你編的  -那個
- you made all that up? - Well...
我自由發揮了一下
I took some liberties.
但  我也說不好  我一開了頭
But, well, I don't know, once it started,
就能清晰地看見了
it came to me so clearly...
-艾瑞克  對嗎  -對  先生
- It's Eric, yeah? - Yes, sir.
抗議人群嗎
The crowd?
對  抱歉  你剛才要說什么
Yes. I'm sorry, what were you about to say?
我無意唐突  先生
I don't mean to overstep, sir...
但外面的人
but the people out there...
我不在乎他們說什么
I don't care what they're saying.
在我看來  人的命運
And the way I see it, a person's destiny is, you know...
是注定的
sealed.
我們踏入了未知領域
We are in uncharted territory here.
好  但是唐尼  幫個忙好嗎
All right. But, Donny, do me a favor, okay?
-讓憲法  -我能說完嗎
- Let the Constitution-- - Can I finish?
等等  讓憲法行使它的職責
Hold on. Just let the Constitution do its job.
好吧  喬  讓我說完一次
Okay, Joe, Joe, I'm gonna finish for once.
現在有選民提起個訴
You've got voters filing individual suits...
-對  -田納西和俄亥俄都有
- Right. - ...in Tennessee and Ohio,
都堆在最高法院了
and they are jammed up in the Supreme Court.
就像別的一切
Like everything else,
這個國家的日常事務被中斷了
the day-to-day workings of this country are on hold.
好  或許是被中斷了  但你猜怎么
Okay, they may be on hold, but guess what?
據我所知
Last time I checked,
大家仍然在領社保支票
everybody was still getting their Social Security checks.
沒錯  但如果達到債務上限了呢
Yeah, but if the debt limit is reached?
拜托  讓我說完
Come on. Let me finish now.
再說一遍  這就是為什么我們有憲法
Again, it's why we have a Constitution.
我知道看上去很混亂
I know it looks messy.
民主就很混亂  但你猜怎么
Democracy's messy. But guess what?
這種亂局是有規律的
There is a method to that madness.
我說不好  喬
I don't know, Joe.
如今是混亂勝過規律
It's more madness than method right now.
如果政府停擺
I mean, if the government does shut down,
那些社保支票或許就要停發
those Social Security checks, they might not go out.
如果政府停擺
If the government shuts down,
誰知道國會還能不能選出總統
who knows if Congress can even pick a president?
眾議院的每個州只有一票
Each state in the House just gets one vote.
那么如果特拉華州和羅德島州這樣的小州
So if smaller states like Delaware and Rhode Island
不能達成共識
can't reach a consensus...
-嗯  -不  是這樣的
- Right. - No, it's true.
如果一兩個
I mean, if one or two of these
非常固執的國會成員
really stubborn members of Congress
決定頑固抵抗  可能要耗數月
decides they're going to hold this up, it could be months.
我正是這個意思
Look, that's what I'm saying.
得到26張選票并不容易
The road to 26 votes is not an easy one.
好吧  時局確實奇怪  米卡
All right. Strange days indeed, Mika.
這些是短篇小說的開頭嗎
So are these the start to short stories?
現在還不是什么  只是片段
They're nothing yet. Fragments.
碎片
Pieces.
顯然這是關于我的
I mean, clearly, this is about me.
這是我母親
This is my mother.
這是我們
And this is us.
-你不能寫  -我要寫
- You can't write-- - I'm writing.
這是我的工作  我是個作家
It's what I do. I'm a writer.
我知道你很不滿  湯姆  但是
I know you're frustrated, Tom, but--
不是不滿
I wouldn't say frustrated.
這是侵犯
Well, it's invasive.
-寫你自己的經歷  -這是我的經歷
- Write about your own experiences. - This is my experience.
聽著  湯姆
Listen, Tom,
我們決定弗蘭西斯和我要留在這里
just because we've decided Francis and I need to stay here,
不代表你也是
doesn't mean you have to.
如果你有事
So if you have things you need to do,
就應該去做
you should go ahead and do them.
我這一天得說服參議院給我投票
I'll be spending my day convincing the Senate to vote for me,
不需要演講
so there's no speeches necessary.
好
Yeah, okay.
你知道嗎  我確實有事情要做
You know what? I do have some things to do.
我需要去找一些人  所以
Some people I need to check in with. So...
湯姆
Tom.
怎么了
Yeah?
什么事
Yes?
準備好了嗎  安德伍德夫人
You ready, Mrs. Underwood?
我會安排一輛車等你
I'll have a car waiting for you.
你想先聽好消息還是壞消息
So do you want the good news or the bad news first?
永遠先聽壞消息
Always the bad.
總統的支持率已跌至19%
The president's approvals are down to 19%.
好消息
And the good?
國會情況更糟
They're worse for Congress.
而你是30%
And you're at 30.
幸好我們現在要說服的是國會
Well, thankfully it's congress we have to convince now,
不是民眾
not the public.
這些是選舉前我們要解決的剩下的參議員
These are the remaining senators we'll target before the vote.
對了  都是女人
All women, by the way.
最大的挑戰將是
The biggest challenges will be
印第安納州的新晉參議員蘇珊·紐曼
Indiana's freshman senator Susan Newman.
憲法律師
The constitutional lawyer?
以及夏威夷的凱芮·奎立馬
And Hawaii's Kerry Kuilima,
她似乎很高興
who seems to be enjoying
終于能有一次實權了
getting to wield a little power for once.
我必須告訴你  國會對同時為
I need to tell you, there is a lot of pushback on the Hill
總統和副總統投票抵觸情緒很高
about the simultaneous vote for president and VP.
國民很擔心這會導致總統副總統不同黨
The country is terrified it'll lead to a split ticket.
有人可能阻撓議事
There's threats of a filibuster.
參議院現在是民主黨的
Well, the Dems won the Senate,
他們想跟眾議院一起投票的
and they want to vote when the House does.
這已經決定了
That decision's been made.
副總統也不會允許議員以任何形式
And the vice president won't allow a filibuster of any kind
阻撓議事
onto the floor.
夫人  你有沒有考慮過這樣的結果
Ma'am, have you contemplated how it could possibly work,
你做康威總統的副總統
you as vice president to President Conway?
不會那樣的
That's not going to happen.
當然
Of course.
我倒是真知道奧古斯都·安德伍德的一件事
I did learn one true thing about Augustus Underwood.
什么事
What?
他死了  真死了
He was dead. Cold.
他的尸體被放在一輛馬車上...
They put him on a cart...
上面有好多有待埋葬的尸體
bunch of dead bodies to bury.
一天一夜之后...
Then, after a full day and night...
他醒了
he woke up.
什么
What?
有人偷走了他的鞋和軍服上的扣子  但是
Someone stole his shoes and the buttons off his uniform, but...
他活過來了
he lived.
幾天后  他趕上了他所在的軍團
Few days later, he caught up to his regiment.
真的嗎
Really?
我得回去面對那些混亂了
I have to get back to the madness.
希望還能再見到你  總統先生
I hope I get to see you again, Mr. President.
艾瑞克...你不參加重演活動時
Eric... what do you do when you're not,
都干些什么
reenacting?
我是一名演員
I'm an actor.
有時候是吧
Sometimes.
只要有人雇  我也可以干其它的
I mean, I'd do a lot more if someone would let me.
現在  我主要做私人教練
So, right now, I'm mostly a personal trainer.
-私人教練  -是的
- A personal trainer? - Yeah.
你知道我的聯系方式
You know where to find me.
還有  總統閣下...
And, sir...
不管情況看起來多糟糕...
no matter how dire things look...
你都能熬出頭的
you're gonna come out of this alive.
你畢竟是安德伍德家的人
You're an Underwood, after all.
不  別耍嘴皮子  埃莉諾
No, don't... don't "Chief-of-staff" me, Eleanor.
不  不要給我他的行程
No, don't give me his schedule.
我不想知道
I don't want to hear
羅梅洛議員在會見選民
about how Congressman Romero is meeting with his constituents
或是滯留在阿西樂特快上了
or stuck on an Acela train.
你叫法齊奧  對嗎
You know, it's Fazio, right?
是這么發音的吧
The pronunciation?
埃莉諾·法齊奧
Eleanor Fazio?
我只是想確認一下
I... I just want to be sure.
因為等總統獲勝  他一定會獲勝的
Because when the president wins, and he is going to win,
我會記得你的
I will remember your name.
我還是需要你過目一下這篇發布稿
I still need you to review this release.
很明顯  目標是
Now, obviously, the goal is
抵住"躲藏"的論調
to combat the "hiding out" narrative,
強調他們正在做的工作
emphasizing the work that they're doing.
-私事嗎  -公事
- Is it a personal matter? - Business.
我只有公事
It's always business.
我會簽好字電郵給你的
I'll e-mail you my sign off.
等等
Wait a second.
我需要他們明天的最新行程
I need an update on their schedule for tomorrow.
-勝利就在眼前  -告訴我你是怎么知道的
- We're almost there. - I want to know how you found out.
如果他需要幫助
If he needs help,
等他入主白宮后隨時可以找我
that can happen after he makes it to the White House.
馬克  你還沒有回答我的問題
Mark, you're not answering my question.
如果他接受治療的消息
If word of treatment,
任何形式的治療  泄露了...
any kind of treatment, got out--
他的朋友給他看了那種治療方法
His friend was showing him the therapy.
-僅此而已  -請不要侮辱我
- That's it. - Please don't insult me.
你以為你是誰
Who do you think you are?
插手我們生活的方方面面
Inserting yourself into every aspect of our lives.
你丈夫的選舉需要幫助
Your husband's campaign needed help.
-我就伸出了援手  -是的  但是...
- Help arrived. - Yes, but--
這原來可是你的意思  對吧
Help that you, most of all, pushed for. Yes?
-誰告訴你虛擬現實療法的  -他自己說的
- Who told you about the VR therapy? - He did.
我們走吧
Let's go.
怎么了
What's going on?
我就是在跟馬克說我非常懷念馬歇爾在的時候
I was just telling Mark how much I miss having Marshall around.
他還在啊
Well, he's still around.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我忘拿包了
I forgot my bag.
就在這里
It's right here.
喂  是的
Hello. Yeah.
是的  他在
Yes, sir, he's right here.
是他
It's him.
議員先生
Congressman.
你根本不知道這可能會多糟
You have no idea how bad this could get.
我們可別遲到
We don't wanna be late.
我萬分贊同
Well, I couldn't agree more.
她可能去了圣達菲
She might have gone to Santa Fe.
你不相信我  是嗎
You don't believe me, do you?
我需要看到點切實的東西  麗薩
I would need to see something, Lisa. Something concrete.
我有照片  我有一張
I have a photo. I have one, but...
聽我說
Listen.
看著我
Look at me.
你不是第一個來找我對安德伍德和他手下
You're not the first person to come here making false claims
提出虛假指控的人了
about Underwood and his cronies.
但我說的是實話
But I'm telling the truth.
但你說的一切都可能是報紙上讀來的
Everything you're saying you could've read in the paper.
我就是這樣知道他的身份的  因為報紙登了
That's how I realized who he was. His picture in the paper.
這樣你的說法就更難證實了  我們在兜圈子
Which makes your story harder to prove. We're talking in circles.
那我車壞掉時  道格·斯坦普開車送我回家呢
What about Doug Stamper driving me home when my car broke down,
還跟我說他叫彼得  是賣保險的
telling me his name was Peter and that he sold insurance?
-沒人能證實你的說法  -瑞秋
- No one can corroborate that story. - Rachel!
瑞秋可以
Rachel could.
-你該吃完  -我不餓
- You should finish that. - I'm not hungry.
或許我餓了  我不知道
Maybe I am. I don't know.
我想感謝你來聯絡我
I want to thank you for reaching out.
我不是說我不相信你
I am not saying I don't believe you.
但已經有足夠可以
But there's already enough evidence out there
扳倒總統的證據了
to take the president down.
這次選舉  會讓他背負更多罪責
And now, with this election, he'll be accountable for even more.
-我確定  -我不在乎
- I'm certain of it. - I don't care.
我不在乎安德伍德  我要你去找道格·斯坦普
I don't care about Underwood. I want you to talk to Doug Stamper.
我要你查明我的...
I want you to find out what happened to my...
算了  拉倒吧
Whatever, forget it.
-等等  -謝謝你的三明治
- Uh. Hold on. - Thanks for the sandwich.
好吧  等等
All right. Hold on.
有一個關于林登·約翰遜的故事我很喜歡
There's a story that I love about LBJ.
那是64或65年的時候
Uh, it was back in '64 or '65.
有個議員在躲他  那議員回到自己的辦公室
A congressman was ducking him... and he came back to his office
總統就坐在他的椅子上
to find the president sitting in his chair...
等著他
waiting for him.
總統一小時內要見到你
The president expects to see you within the hour.
法齊奧小姐會告訴你具體情況
Miss Fazio can give you the specifics.
-他戴著牛仔帽  -什么
- He was wearing his cowboy hat. - What?
約翰遜總統  你漏掉了故事最精彩的部分
President Johnson. You left out the best part of the story.
我們昨晚玩到那里閉店  多謝邀請
We closed the place down last night. Thanks for the invite.
我們幾個人今晚還去那里
Bunch of us are headed back to the same spot tonight,
要一起來嗎
if you wanna come.
好啊  他今天午飯吃的晚  4點才會回來
Cool. Uh, he has a late lunch today. Won't be back till 4:00.
-我就是來送這個  -好
- Oh, I just needed to drop this for him. - Sure.
下次  問就好
Next time, just ask.
今晚見
See you tonight.
你賭了一把  但輸了
You gambled and you lost.
其實  跟八周前比  我黨團席位增多了
Actually, my bloc gained seats more than eight weeks ago.
我猜你就是為這事找我
Which I suspect is why I'm here.
別高估了你的位置
Don't overestimate your position.
或是低估了我的
Or underestimate mine.
你還沒當選總統呢  先生
You still haven't been elected president, sir.
是啊  但如果黨派背棄了你
Yeah, but the presidency won't matter
總統之職就無所謂了吧
once the party turns its back on you, will it?
等鮑勃·博奇教訓好了你其他的綿羊
When Bob Birch puts all the rest of your sheep in line,
你會求著不被孤立
you'll be begging to come in from the cold.
兩年后  你會回到鳳凰城
And two years from now, you'll be back in Phoenix
一遍遍在腦海里回顧這一刻
replaying this very moment over and over again in your mind
意識到  這就是結束的開始
and realizing it was the beginning of the end.
帕特里夏·惠特克和民主黨
Patricia Whittaker and the Democratic Party
會跟你撇清關系
will wipe their hands of you.
-我是忠于黨的  -那是應該的
- I'm loyal to the party. - As you should be.
你應該這么說
As you should say.
但說真的
But really...
你有什么籌碼
what's your leverage?
委員會  那已經完了
The committee? That's done.
瞧  你已經獻了身  艾力克斯
You see, you've already put out, Alex,
威爾·康威卻不打算帶你去舞會
and Will Conway is not taking you to the prom.
我跟州長的談話
My conversations with the governor
和我可能的立場...
and any position that I may or may not have--
聽聽自己的話  你相信自己嗎
Oh, listen to yourself. Do you even believe you?
你作為一個
You are awfully confident
已經輸了一次選舉的人  好自信啊
for someone who's already lost the election once.
幫個忙  暫時忘記總統的事
Do me a favor. Forget the presidency for just a moment.
你沒有...資本
You don't have... the capital
來推動你掀起的國會革命
to build on the congressional revolution that you've started,
不管是政治上還是其他的
politically or otherwise.
我們的運動想讓事態爆發
Our movement wants to explode things--
得了  少拿那套革新派公關套路我
Oh, please. Spare me your progressive PR bullshit.
你和他們想要的東西一樣
You want what they all want.
權力  更好的地位
Access. A better seat at the table.
你的名字在他人之前
Your name before the rest.
這我可以給你
And that is something that I can give you.
你想換取多少選票呢
And how many votes do you want in exchange?
你不斷增長的黨團給我三張就行
Just three from your ever-growing bloc
我就能在關鍵代表團獲得勝利
would assure me the win in key delegations.
具體點
Specifically?
緬因州  威斯康星州和新罕布什爾還未定
Maine, Wisconsin and New Hampshire are still in play.
三個全要
All three?
我相信你  議員  想知道為什么嗎
I believe in you, Congressman. Do you wanna know why?
說吧
Tell me.
因為我相信野心
Because I trust ambition.
-那這是直截了當的賄賂嘍  -不  議員
- So this is a straight-up bribe. - Oh, no, Congressman.
賄賂是你可以拒絕的
A bribe is something you can refuse.
鑒于你的經驗沒有我豐富
Now, since you haven't been around the block as many times as I have,
我來教教你這事怎么辦吧
let me walk you through how this works.
抱歉  總統  但我知道是怎么回事
Excuse me, Mr. President, but I do know how this is done.
那太好了
Oh, well, that's good to hear.
我從緬因州開始吧  她欠我的
I'll start with Maine. She owes me.
我們以前見過一次的  總統先生
You know, we did meet once before, Mr. President.
2012年大會的一次晚宴上
At a dinner, during the 2012 convention.
-我還想向你自我介紹來著  -然后呢
- I tried to introduce myself to you... - And?
-你不記得我了  是嗎  -為什么要記得呢
- You don't remember, do you? - Why would I?
主持人為什么那么在意布洛哈特的意見
Why is the moderator so interested in Brockhart's opinion?
所有人都突然忘記我才是總統候選人了嗎
Has everyone suddenly forgotten now I'm at the top of the ticket?
當然沒有
No, of course not.
結束了嗎
Are we done here?
是啊  我們談談明天的日程吧
Yeah. We should talk about tomorrow's schedule.
目前票數不錯
Uh, vote's looking good now.
我們還得盡量多找些議員談
We still need to talk to as many congressmen as we can.
你去安排  然后打給我們
Well, you figure it out and give us a call.
別再安排針對軍事委員會的活動了
And, uh, enough with the events targeting the Armed Services.
我們在這邊拉票已經到極限了
We got as many Congress people as we could get out of this.
別介意  將軍  但我們該分頭行動  好嗎
No offense, General, but we need to divide and conquer. Okay?
威爾  我之前跟馬克談了
Will, I was speaking with Mark...
-怎么  -我想告訴你
- Yeah. - ...and I want you to know,
如果你需要談什么  我隨時奉陪
if you need to talk about anything, I'm available.
我唯一需要的支持  將軍
The only support I need, General...
就是一個副總統對總統的支持  好嗎
is that of a vice president to his president. Okay?
塔伯特參議員的首要考慮是經濟適用房
Senator Talbert's priorities are affordable housing
和堵住企業稅務漏洞
and closing corporate tax loopholes.
尤其是高等教育普及
And access to higher education especially.
通話在10點
The call is in ten.
艾丹·麥卡倫為什么跑了
Why did Aidan Macallan run away?
什么
What?
麥卡倫為什么跑了
Why did Macallan run away?
我也不知道
I wish I could tell you.
時間不多了
Clock's ticking.
請給我湯姆·耶茨司機的號碼
Yes, give me Tom Yates' driver's number, please.
喂
Yes.
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
紐約
New York.
你一路開去了紐約
You drove all the way to New York?
在哪
Where?
他跟誰在一起
Who's he with?
我不知道  一個女人  年紀較長
I don't know. A woman. Older.
我不知道那要怎么做  夫人
I don't know how that'll work, ma'am.
是  我試試
Yes. Yes, I'll try.
不  我理解你的擔憂  參議員
No, I understand your concern, Senator.
學生貸款改革是你的優先考慮
Student loan reform is a priority for you,
那么它就也是總統和我的優先考慮
so it will be a priority for the president and me.
是的  沒錯
Yes. Yes, I do.
露易絲  你是黨派中流砥柱
Well, Louise, you as a pillar of the party,
如果你明天能幫我  我會感激不盡
it will be much appreciated if I can get your help tomorrow.
到時就你和我  還有幾個你的
And it'll just be you and me and a couple of your...
參議院女同事
female colleagues in the Senate.
好  那么我期待與你有成效地談談
Okay, well, I look forward to a productive dialogue.
-遲到總比不來好  -抱歉我錯過了晚餐
- Better late than never. - Sorry I missed dinner.
為什么坐后面
Why the back?
我在假裝你是優步  幫幫忙
I'm pretending you're an Uber. Just help me out.
我的小姑子  你沒來她就來了
My sister-in-law. She came when you couldn't.
你覺得死者會鄙視我們嗎
Do you think the dead judge us?
不會
No.
你最喜歡他做什么
What did he do that you liked the most?
在床上
Here... in bed.
坐姿最好
Sitting up was the best.
腿纏著彼此
Legs around each other.
他會把右手
He'd run his right hand
伸到我脖子后面  插進我的頭發里拽著
up the back of my neck into my hair and pull it.
把我的頭發和腦袋往后拽
My hair and my head back...
然后呢
And?
然后用另一只手  把我拉進拉出
And with the other hand, he'd pull me in and out.
他始終看著我
Always looking at me.
看到我
Seeing me.
你要我那么做嗎
You want me to do that?
嗯
Yeah.
這里真好  幾乎聽不到他們的吼聲
It's so nice in here. You can hardly hear them.
相信我  我聽得到的
Oh, trust me, I can hear them.
加上新罕布什爾  多少了
With New Hampshire, it's what?
24  加緬因州25
Twenty-four. With Maine, 25.
-如果拿下威斯康星就是26  -湯姆呢
- Twenty-six if we get Wisconsin. - Where's Tom?
他去喘口氣了
He needed to get some air.
-威斯康星很頑固  -那還有誰
- Wisconsin is being stubborn. - Then who else?
愛荷華  或許科羅拉多  那是24  25
Iowa, maybe Colorado, 24, 25.
你的曾曾曾祖父奧古斯都怎么樣了
How was your great-great-great-grandfather Augustus?
他叫艾瑞克
He goes by Eric.
艾瑞克
Eric.
他很欣賞我的手藝
He admired my craftsmanship.
-我們該爭取一下北達科他  -同意
- We should make a play for North Dakota. - Agreed.
在參議院  你應該可以拉密蘇里的票
In the Senate, I think you can swing some votes from Missouri.
你問莉安麥卡倫的事了嗎
Did you ask LeAnn about Macallan?
她并不知情  我相信她
She didn't know anything. I believe her.
我們又得戒了
We have to quit again.
否則  會害死我們的
Otherwise, they'll kill us.
麥卡倫不見蹤影  但他去過那兒  留下了財物
No Macallan. He was there, though. Left his belongings.
國家警察那里有消息嗎
Anything from the National Police?
沒有  中情局的內部人士
No. CIA's man in the palace
甚至不確定他是否還在雅加達
isn't even sure he's still in Jakarta.
他們會找到他的  莉安  我只能說這么多
They'll find him, LeAnn. That's all I can give you.
多謝幫忙
I appreciate your help.
凱芮  蘇珊  需要點什么
Kerry, Susan, what can I get you?
-不用  謝謝  -水就行
- I'm fine, thanks. - I'm good with water.
-你呢  露易絲  -你喝什么
- What about you, Louise? - What are you having?
-伏特加加冰  -給我也來一杯
- Splash of vodka on ice. - Make it two.
蘇珊和我來的路上談了  克萊爾
Susan and I were talking on the way over, Claire.
這場選舉的混亂讓我們
This election mess has left us
都面臨著一些可怕的可能性
all facing some scary possibilities.
-康威拿下眾議院  -這還遠非定數
- Conway wins in the House-- - Which is far from inevitable.
但如果真發生總統副總統不同黨
But if a split ticket were to happen...
那對國家會不利的
it would be bad for this country.
不  康威才對國家不利
No, Conway is what would be bad for this country.
希望眾議院能做出正確選擇
Let's hope the House does the right thing.
但就參議院而言
But as far as the Senate,
我很高興有唐納德·布萊斯掌舵
I am very grateful that we have Donald Blythe steering that ship.
安德伍德夫人  我很抱歉這么說
Mrs. Underwood, I'm sorry to say this,
但不管你能拿出什么
but no matter what you're offering here,
我都不能支持總統
I can't support the president.
也因此不能支持你
And, by extension, I can't support you.
不是你的問題  克萊爾  是他
It's not you, Claire. It's him.
蘇珊和我在這事上的意見是一致的
Susan and I are on the same page about this.
如果重點不是弗蘭西斯·安德伍德呢
What if this isn't about Francis Underwood, huh?
前途大好的是克萊爾·安德伍德
It's Claire Underwood who has the promising future.
我希望一個女人入主白宮
I want a woman in the White House.
如果她得從副總統做起  那好
And if she has to start as a vice president, fine.
但時候到了
But it's time.
-時候到了  -我贊同  露易絲
- It's time. - I hear that, Louise,
但我直說吧
but I'll say it...
投票給你  就是投給弗蘭克·安德伍德
A vote for you is a vote for Frank Underwood.
我理解你們對弗蘭西斯歷史的擔憂  真的
Listen, I understand your concerns about Francis' record. I do.
如果康威贏了
If Conway wins,
難道你們不希望有個民主黨人克制著他嗎
wouldn't you want a Democrat to keep him in check?
如果給我投票不等于給弗蘭西斯投票呢
And what if a vote for me isn't necessarily a vote for Francis?
21票確定是你  先生
Twenty-one promised for you, sir.
康威是23
Twenty-three for Conway.
兩個僵持  四個未知
Two deadlocked. Four unknown.
但我覺得黨團會議之后情況會變動
But I think things will shift once they caucus.
-好  叫他進來  -是  先生
- All right, let's bring him in. - Yes, sir.
-請坐  -我不久留
- Have a seat. - I won't be long.
那就站著吧
Well, then, stand like a man
像個不知是否該坐下的人
who doesn't know whether to sit or not.
羅梅洛議員  你為我帶來好消息了嗎
Congressman Romero, do you have good news for me?
你的革新人士想明白了嗎
Have your progressives seen the light?
我已經盡力了  總統先生  我無法說服他們
I did what I could, Mr. President. I couldn't sway the bloc.
無法  還是不愿
Couldn't... or wouldn't?
緬因和新罕布什爾還不明朗
Maine and New Hampshire are noncommittal.
沃考特議員在讓威斯康星支持康威
Congressman Wolcott is turning Wisconsin for Conway.
告訴我點別的事實
Tell me a different truth.
他們不聽我的
They aren't listening to me.
他們相信  與讓康威當選相比
They believe supporting you would do more damage
支持你會給民主黨和國家造成更大損害
to the Democratic Party and the country than a Conway presidency.
很遺憾  竟然走到這一步
Well, I am sorry that it has come to this.
我也是  我們肯定還會再見的  先生
As am I. I'm sure we'll meet again, sir.
是啊  但你走之前  好好看看這間屋子
Yes, but before you go, just take a look around this room.
仔細看每處細節  每個方面
Study every detail, every aspect.
因為這是你最后一次踏進這里了
Because this is the last time you will ever step foot in here.
抱歉我沒幫上更多忙
I'm sorry I couldn't be of more help.
想想吧  你本能讓自己因為很多其他事
And to think you could have made yourself memorable
被世人銘記的
in so many other ways.
我會確保他再進不了其他委員會  先生
I'll make sure he never sees another committee, sir.
不  他希望我們還擊  讓他感覺更強大
Oh, no. He wants us to put up a fight, make him feel bigger.
他只不過是看了民調數據  就以為我有麻煩
He's just read some polls and thinks I'm in trouble.
所以他才攻擊我
That's why he's coming after me.
好吧  我們有48小時
All right, we have 48 hours.
我得攻下科羅拉多  穩住田納西
I have to work Colorado and shore up Tennessee.
但哪怕不惜一切  也要讓
But Maine, Wisconsin and New hampshire
緬因  威斯康星和新罕布什爾回心轉意
must be turned by any means necessary.
所有黨團會議周四中午之前都會結束
All caucusing will end by noon on Thursday,
下午兩點
and then the vote in both
參眾兩院開始投票
the House and the Senate is scheduled for 2:00.
我不做決定  查克  我只是傳達而已
Well... I don't make the decisions, Chuck. I just relay them.
不  不  目前不做聲明
No. No, there will not be a statement at this time.
因為投票結果出來前無話可說
Well, because there's nothing to state until after the vote.
關上門
Close the door.
嗯  對
Right. Yes.
對
Yes.
求你別再逼我說"對"了
Yeah, please don't make me say yes again.
美國現在真是瘋了
Crazy days in these United States.
你想告訴我  是什么重要到
So you wanna tell me what was so important
我得放你進來
I had to get you through the gates?
有個叫麗薩·威廉姆斯的女孩來過
Girl named Lisa Williams came in.
說她曾是瑞秋·波斯納的女朋友
Says she was Rachel Posner's girlfriend.
她說道格·斯坦普認識瑞秋
Said Doug Stamper knew Rachel.
覺得他可能和瑞秋失蹤有關
Feels like maybe he was involved in her disappearance.
她說道格·斯坦普這個名字了嗎
And she said the words "Doug Stamper"?
瑞秋·波斯納失蹤的時間
Rachel Posner went missing around the time
正好是斯坦普被劫車  腦袋被砸的時候
Stamper was carjacked and had his head bashed in.
這個麗薩覺得
And this Lisa thinks...
她也不太確定
Well, she's not sure exactly.
她能證明其中有聯系嗎
Well, can she prove a connection?
現在都只是直覺
It's all instinct at this point.
拜托
Come on.
你要是想參觀白宮
You want a tour of the White House,
可以直接跟我說嘛
you could just straight up ask me for one.
-漢默施密特  -他看重這事嗎
- Hammerschmidt. - Is he making anything of it?
還不  但關于她的資料已經在他桌上了
Not yet. But the information about her is on the top of his desk.
麗薩·威廉姆斯
Lisa Williams.
格雷森先生  三號線有人找
Mr. Grayson, you have a call on line three.
我得工作了
Well, I gotta get back to it.
要是湯姆繼續跟進她  就告訴我
If Tom follows up on her, let me know.
-謝謝你給的通行證  -是臨時的
- Thanks for the pass. - It's temporary.
好吧
Okay.
-莉安·哈維  -你總熬夜
- LeAnn Harvey. - Always burning the midnight oil.
-艾丹  -你準備好來找我了嗎
- Aidan? - You ready to join me?
你知道你把我推進了多危險的境地嗎
Do you have any idea how much jeopardy you have put me in?
你應該趁還有機會逃出來
You should've gotten out when you had the chance.
你覺得你就逃出來了
You think you're out?
-聽著  我需要你幫我個忙  -你在哪
- Listen, I need you to do me a favor. - Where are you?
讓聯調局  中情局
Get the FBI, CIA,
和其他在找我的人都停下  馬上
and whoever else is looking for me to stop, now.
好  艾丹  你就
Okay, Aidan, you know, just...
先回來  我們一起想辦法
come back here, and we will figure this out together.
要是他們繼續找我
If they keep coming after me,
我就開始泄露關于安德伍德夫婦的秘密
I will start leaking things about the Underwoods.
你不想那么做的
You don't wanna do that.
你不知道你現在是在為什么人工作  莉安
You have no idea who you're working for, LeAnn.
該死
God damn it.
有新情況向總統匯報嗎
You have an update for the president?
我今天基本上一直在忙著應付參議員
I've been juggling senators most of the day.
你那緬因州的議員呢
And your congressman from Maine?
依然是我朋友的父親  依然沒時間見面
Is still my friend's father and is still too busy to meet.
威斯康星和新罕布什爾也一樣
So was Wisconsin and New Hampshire,
我逼他們就見到了
until I forced them to.
你有你的風格  我有我的
You have your style, I have mine.
總統不在乎風格  莉安
The president doesn't care about style, LeAnn.
周四前把議員的票拉到位就行
Just get the congressman by the vote on Thursday.
威爾剛進來了
Will just walked in.
嗯
Yeah.
行
Okay.
再聯系  拜
Talk soon. Bye.
-你媽媽  -對  她向你問好
- That your mom? - Yeah. She sends her best.
好吧
Yeah.
-查理人呢  -在客廳
- Where's Charlie? - In the living room.
莉莉在小房間玩
Lily's playing in the den.
-你要去哪  -我該換衣服了
- Where are you going? - I should change.
-你一直躲著我  漢娜  -拜托
- You keep walking away from me, Hannah. - Oh, please.
你為什么邀請他來
Why would you invite him here?
這個時候
Now?
他是朋友  你的朋友
He's a friend. He's your friend.
我想也許...
And I thought maybe...
你會有興趣看一看
it'd be something that you'd be interested in looking at.
我在盡力而為
I'm doing all I can.
-盡力而為  -是的
- All you can? - Yes.
質疑我
Like doubt me?
以為你比我更了解我自己的精神狀況
Like think that you know better what's in my mind than I do?
要知道  是你告訴馬克的
You know, you're the one who told Mark.
我還得否認我跟那事有關
I had to deny I had anything to do with it.
要知道這些人  漢娜  厄舍和馬歇爾
See, these people, Hannah... Usher and Marshall...
他們是雇工  不能信他們
they're hired hands. They can't be trusted.
布洛哈特也是為了自己
And Brockhart, he's in it for himself.
但你...親愛的  我的愛人
But... but you, my darling, my love--
-別說了  -別說什么
- Stop it. - Stop what?
你能怎么樣  帶孩子回娘家
What are you gonna do? Take the kids and go to your mom?
你不會這么做的
As if you would.
你連白宮的瓷器都挑好了
You already picked out the White House china.
你最大的心愿就是當上總統
You want this more than anything. To be president.
這也成了我的心愿  你膽敢來指責我
Don't you dare judge me now that I want it, too.
是  議員  安排航程也算賄賂
Yes, Congressman, but flights are considered bribes.
是  議員  我們擔心的不是你的酒駕
Yes, Congressman, it's not your DUIs that concern us,
而是你女兒的
it's your daughter's.
那你本該把開銷藏得更深
Well, you should've done a better job hiding the payouts.
拜托
I mean, really.
嗯  我相信你是  他多大來著
Yes, I'm sure you are... but how old was he again?
對  他參加過合唱團  對吧
Yes, and he was in the choir, is that right?
但你沒法把郵件刪得不留痕跡
But you can never erase an e-mail,
我過世的姑姑都知道
even my dead aunt knows that.
好吧  你盡快回復我
Well, get back to me as soon as you can.
-怎么樣  -緬因州終于搞定了  先生
- So? - Maine finally looks solid, sir.
但新罕布什爾還沒有
New Hampshire doesn't, though.
我坐在這里好幾個小時
I've been sitting in here for hours
想方設法取得了一些成效
busting my ass, getting some results.
我們本應拿下新罕布什爾的
We should have secured New Hampshire.
莉安怎么拿下緬因州的
How did LeAnn get Maine?
對方欠她人情
She cashed in a favor.
那你為什么不能用同一招
Well, why couldn't you do the same goddamn thing?
我想不通
It doesn't make sense.
我以為我說服他了
I thought I had him. I mean...
不只是新罕布什爾  威斯康星本來也該拿下的
And it's not just New Hampshire. Wisconsin should've folded.
本來
Should have?
怎么回事  道格  你怎么了
What's going on, Doug? What's happening?
是你的投入  還是忠心出了問題
Is there some issue with your commitment? Your loyalty?
什么
What?
或許你就不值得我信任
Perhaps you just aren't worthy of my trust.
我為你費盡心力
I have given everything to you.
我的整個職業生涯幾乎都給了你  弗蘭克
Almost the entirety of my professional life, Frank.
你注意語氣
You watch your tone.
我做的那些事...
The things I've done...
為了保住你的位子  我做的那些事...
The things that I have done to help keep you here,
你居然還質疑我的忠心
and you're gonna question my loyalty?
如果我們不能贏
Well, if we can't win,
那我們得確保康威也不能贏
we have to make sure that Conway doesn't either.
緬因州支持我們  那他就拿不到26票
Maine coming over only means he won't get to 26.
僵局不是勝局  但至少...
A deadlock isn't a win. But at least...
抱歉  道格  我剛才失態了
I'm sorry, Doug. I was out of line.
我們繼續工作吧
Let's get back to work.
不只是他如何處理了那些數據
It's not just what he did with all the data.
艾丹之前能接觸到一切
Aidan had access to everything.
我們得讓中情局和聯調局不去查他
We need to get the CIA and FBI off his trail,
我需要你的幫助
and I need your help.
你在制造麻煩  莉安
You're causing problems, LeAnn,
我們現在最要不得麻煩了
which is the last thing that we can afford right now.
麥卡倫是作繭自縛
Macallan sealed his own fate.
我拿下了緬因州  道格
I delivered Maine, Doug,
你可沒處理好新罕布什爾
which is more than you can say about New Hampshire.
算我欠你人情
I'll owe you.
還不夠
Not enough.
總統跟你說過艾丹的事嗎
Has the president spoken to you about Aidan at all?
沒有
No.
他在狙殺名單上嗎
Is he on a kill list?
美利堅合眾國沒有狙殺名單  莉安
The United States of America doesn't have kill lists, LeAnn.
我是唯一阻止麥卡公布他手上的東西的人
I am the only thing preventing Mac from releasing what he has.
我猜不管那是什么  你也牽涉其中
And my guess is, whatever it is, it'll implicate you, too.
我錯了嗎  道格
Am I wrong, Doug?
米切爾參議員身邊的人告訴了我這消息
Someone close to Senator Mitchell woke me up with the news.
讓副總統接電話
Get me the vice president on the phone.
沒用
That is not going to help.
你打算怎么處理
Well, how do you intend on dealing with it?
唐納德
Donald.
-別這么做  -克萊爾
- Don't do it. - Claire--
我知道你和米切爾參議員在謀劃什么
I know what you and Senator Mitchell were planning.
做你本該做的事
Do what you were supposed to do.
取消阻撓議事  好讓參議院能投票
Move the anti-filibuster measure forward so the Senate can vote
-選我擔任副總統  -不行
- and elect me vice president. - No.
-不行  -各方聲音都應該被聽到
- No? - All voices should be heard
出于對美國人民的尊重
out of respect for the American people
也因為今天參議院投票的重要性
and the gravity of the vote before the Senate today,
自1825年起  這還是首次
the first like this since 1825.
眾議院即將投票  唐納德  怎么回事
The House is about to vote, Donald. What is going on?
我們把這事弄完  你就能回家了
Let's get this done so you can go home.
看上去康威要贏了
It looks like Conway is going to win.
不管別人跟你說了什么
And no matter what people have told you,
參議院會投給布洛哈特
the Senate is voting for Brockhart.
-國家高于政黨  克萊爾  -你在耍滑頭嗎
- It's country over party, Claire. - Are you flexing?
我想拖到眾議院完成投票
I'm stalling until the House vote happens
好讓參議院據結果投票
and then the Senate votes accordingly.
你要那樣對待
You'd do that to the party
你將全部事業傾注其中的政黨嗎
to which you've devoted your entire career?
國家需要透明和決議
The country needs clarity and resolution.
那是最重要的事
That's the most important thing.
四年后還會有選舉
There'll be another election in four years.
但聽我說
But look...
弗蘭西斯昏迷時  我看到了你的樣子
I saw you when Francis was in the coma.
當得到機會時你展現出的能力
What you're capable of when given the opportunity.
你今后還有機會  我會為你投票
You still have a shot down the road. I'd vote for you.
不管你怎么想  我知道我票數夠了
Whatever you think, I know I have the numbers.
我不這么認為
I don't think so.
但拜托
But come on.
你不像他  耐心點
You're not like him. Be patient.
你是個傻瓜  唐納德  一直都是
You're a fool, Donald. You always were.
你和你三句不離的那個蠢亡妻
You and your dumb, dead wife that you never, ever shut up about.
有原則  理想主義
Principled? Idealistic?
捍衛人民  你實際做過什么
A champion for the people? What did you ever actually do?
什么也沒有
Nothing.
偉大的斗士  我看不是
The great crusader? I don't think so.
你只是喜歡你現在這副傻瓜的樣子
You just liked the position of the bumbling idiot that you are.
樂觀主義者  理想主義者
The optimist. The idealist.
你太喜歡了以至于你甚至不能達成一筆協議
You loved it so much that you couldn't even make a deal
或者推進一件事
or move a single thing forward.
你什么也沒有留下
You have a legacy of nothing.
取消阻撓議事  讓共和黨別礙事
Sign the measure, get the Republicans off the floor,
馬上開始投票
start the vote now.
你知道我剛剛意識到什么嗎
Do you know what I just realized?
你的姓名首字母
Your initials...
少了N和T[賤人]
they're missing an "N" and a "T".
投票無結果  總統先生
The vote is inconclusive, Mr. President.
你和康威都沒達到26票
Neither you nor Conway to 26.
還有機會  克萊爾怎么樣
Still alive. What about Claire?
這不可能
This is impossible.
我和你一樣驚訝
I'm as surprised as you are.
緬因州  毫無征兆
Maine. There was no heads-up on that.
我知道這令人沮喪  這本該結束了
Look, I know this is frustrating. It should be over.
我是總統
I... I'm the president.
我不管他們說什么  我
I don't care what they say, I...
我就是該死的美國總統
I'm fucking President of the United States.
不  你不是
No, you're not.
直到眾議院做出決定
The vice president will be acting president
副總統將代總統職
for as long as it takes the House to decide.
我該去打幾個電話
I should make some calls.
美國總統選舉的過程是  選舉日注冊選民投票
(有的州在選舉日前也可以投票  但有的州只能在當日投票)
投票結束后開始計票  媒體根據計票結果  用自己的模型得出各州結果
拿到271張選舉人票為勝  如果是平局  則由眾議院投票決定總統
但媒體公布結果后  具體的計票還要繼續  直到統計出所有的選票
如果哪個州結果過于相近  按部分州的法律  會自動啟動重新計票
計票結束后  選舉委員會確定勝者  一般由州長來簽名認證
需注意的是  根據法律  投票日選的其實不是總統
而是"選舉人"  也就各州的"投票代表"
而選舉委員會和州長認證的  也是各州的選舉人名單
選舉人需在大選后去華盛頓參加選舉人會議
跟其他州的代表一起  再投一次票  那一次才算真正選出總統
當然大選夜之后的選舉人再度投票  只是象征性的
不過美國只有29個州有法律規定  選舉人在華盛頓開選舉人會時
必須根據本州的選舉結果投票  所以會出現個別不忠誠的選舉人
在最后投票時  選擇跟本州選民選舉結果不同的候選人
另外在1876年大選出現選派選舉人時產生爭議的情況后
1877年國會立法  規定如果各州的選舉人人選有爭議
則由國會來決定該州的選舉人  另外這個法律還規定
各州必須在選舉人會議前6天向國會提交選舉認證結果
在選舉夜  媒體根據自己的模型判斷勝負
但在法律上  必須所有的票都統計結束
由負責選舉的官員進行公證后  結果才正式生效